GARY JOEL WHITE

Hi, I'm Gary, a Front-End developer with over 4 years of experience, including 1 year specialising in TypeScript and React. Originally from the UK and currently based in Leipzig, I'm eager to relocate further west. Find out more about me and my work.

Front-End Developer Leipzig, Germany +49 159 0148 1213 gary909@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

FRONT-END DEVELOPER (DEC 2023 - NOW)

MacroSolutions GmbH, Leipzig, DE

Responsible for maintaining, improving and developing new features into the frontend of our intra-logistics warehouse software with a strong focus on UX|UI. Successfully completed several key projects, including:

• Development from concept to code with testing using agile methodologies

• Set up API communication with the backend to retrieve stock from automated guided vehicles • Implemented User Authentication and Permission Management with secure login and session management • Pagination: Enhanced the handling of large datasets and increased performance of warehouse results data • Conducted Code Reviews

FRONT-END DEVELOPER (AUG 2019 - AUG 2023)

Lodgit Hotelsoftware GmbH, Leipzig, DE

In charge of maintaining, updating and implementing new features for the company website utilising Contao CMS (HTML, CSS, Javascript).

• Created custom websites and booking pages for clients • Developed mock-ups for new software implementations • Monitored and optimised system performance • Tracked & improved SEO performance using SEMrush, Screaming Frog and Google Search Console • Ensured legal GDPR compliance across company websites • Collaborated with cross-functional teams and stakeholders

TRANSMISSION CONTROLLER (2002 - 2019)

Argiva/Phantasia/Frame 25 Recruitment, Oxfordshire, UK

Responsible for managing and overseeing broadcast output for multiple digital TV channels for a variety of clients such as ESPN, BBC Poland, Disney, Channel 5, Sony and Technicolor. Monitoring of Live broadcast, pre-recorded content, commercials and video feeds. Handling technical faults.

OPERATIONS ASSISTANT (2001 - 2002)

British Forces Broadcasting Services, Gerrards Cross, UK Assistance, Audio engineering, digital editing and maintaining equipment.

EDUCATION

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP (MARCH - MAY 2019)

Ironhack, Berlin, 9 week Bootcamp

Web Dev bootcamp covering the fundamentals of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, TypeScript, Express, MongoDB, testing & agile methodologies.

ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING (2013 - 2014)

International Correspondence Schools, Bachelor of Technology (BTEC)

Electricity & Circuit Theory, Inductance, Capacitance & Solid State Devices, Electronic Applications, Analog & Digital Circuits.

SOUND ENGINEERING WITH MUSIC TECHNOLOGY (1999 - 2001)

Amersham & Wycombe College, BTEC + Higher National Diploma

Acoustics, Music Technology, Sound Design, Recording & Media Business.

LINKS

Personal Website Blog GitHub LinkedIn

HARD SKILLS

Webdev: HTML, CSS, Javascript/TypeScript, React, Git, SEO, Contao CMS, Unit testing (Jest), Adobe Photoshop/ Illustrator Hardware: C++, Arduino, KiCAD, Analog/Digital Electronics VR: C#, Unity, Visual Studio, Blender

CERTIFICATES

XR Terra: 4 week VR developer course (Unity).

Udemy: The Complete Web Dev Bootcamp (65 hour online course).

Udacity: Android Development, scholarship funded by google.

HOBBIES

DIY Synthesizers (combining hardware & software).

VR game/app creation using Unity.

Pizza making (and eating).

Vespa repair (ongoing).

